字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
最快首发美剧日剧下载请登录
字幕组网站www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：王大可 Reginamoon 小暴徒 想名字好难 Charl 木浅薰 Timothy
翻译：HOLA 某羽 dzysteven  校对：油炸电风扇   木浅薰
时间轴：壬虚浪影  今  Spohy
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第六季   第三集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on "Suits"...
我跟你没有任何过节
I don't have anything against you,
我当然不会为了一个陌生人
but I'm not gonna cause trouble with a guy like that
去招惹那样一个人
for someone I've never even met.
所以如果他想让我换几个小时的房间  那我就换
So if he wants me to switch for a few hours, I'm switching.
要是他在里面出了什么事
If something happens to him in there,
我绝对不会原谅你的
I will never forgive you.
-什么事  哈维  -帮我保护迈克・罗斯
- What do you want, Harvey? - Help me protect Mike Ross.
他和我抓的一个人被关在一起  那人可不是吃素的
He's in there with a guy I put away, and the guy is no joke.
但你要我做什么
What am I supposed to do?
我要你把那个人转到别的监狱
You're supposed to move the guy to another prison.
我们合作那么久的时间里
You got a lot of balls saying that to me
你一直都知道他是冒牌货
when the entire time we were working together,
居然还敢来跟我说这话
you knew the kid was a fraud.
我不需要你的原谅  肖恩
I don't need your forgiveness, Sean.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
你想跟我一对一  来吧
You want me one-on-one, you got it.
我打算用这个  而他们会按住你
I'm gonna use this, and they're gonna hold you.
-不不不  -怎么回事
- No! - What's going on here?
你为什么带警卫一起回来
Why'd you come back with a guard?
我那么做不是为了让你原谅我
I didn't do it to get you to forgive me.
我当初就不该让他进来
I never should have let him in here in the first place.
我都还不知道你的名字
I don't even know your name.
凯文  凯文・米勒
Kevin. Kevin Miller.
路易  你的想法是对的
Louis, you have the right idea,
但方法错了
but the wrong execution.
如果我们想看起来像个律所
If we're going to look like a real firm,
我们需要把这些办公室转租出去
we need to do something about subletting these offices.
我会处理
I'll take care of it.
请问我的申请还有什么问题吗
So, is everything on my application in order?
-没有了  -那就好
- Yes, it is. - Good.
那样的话  就继续谈一些细节吧
Because in that case, I'd like to get down to the particulars.
别管那个申请了
Forget the application.
我需要知道你是一个什么样的人
I need to know what the hell kind of man you are.
什么意思
Excuse me?
你们公司的碳排放准则是什么
What's your firm's carbon footprint?
-路易  你又来了  -碳排放
- Louis, not again. - Carbon footprint?
-我们是一家律所  我为什么要  -天哪
- We're a law firm, why would I-- - Jesus Christ.
迈阿密还有五年就要被水淹了
Miami's gonna be underwater in five years,
你们却没有环保政策
and you don't have a goddamn green policy?
就这样吧  这次面试结束了
You know what? This interview's over.
面试  这不是租约谈判吗
Interview? This was supposed to be a lease negotiation.
带着你的说辞快滚吧
Tell your story walking, jerk-off.
天哪  路易
Goddamn it, Louis.
这已经是你
That is the fifth tenant
用一些扯淡话吓走的第五个租客了
you have scared away because of some bullshit.
-这不是扯淡  杰西卡  -真的吗
- This isn't bullshit, Jessica. - Really?
那你从什么时候开始在意环境
Since when do you care about the environment?
转基因黄瓜
Or genetically modified cucumbers?
又或是同性恋人群困境的呢
Or the plight of the LGBT community?
这都是我非常关心的话题
Those are legitimate causes close to my heart.
你这是在无理取闹
You're being ridiculous.
如果法国人能够再无理取闹一点
Yeah, well, had the French been more ridiculous,
那他们也不会
they wouldn't have the Nazis goose-stepping
被纳粹统治六年了
through their streets for six years.
你真的要拿这两件事做比较吗
Are you really comparing this to that?
我坚持这个观点
I stand by that statement.
那就也注意一下这件事
Then stand by this.
明天之前再找不到新的租客
You don't find a new tenant by tomorrow,
那你就自己掏租金吧
then the rent is coming out of your pocket.
所以以后我们在餐厅要一起吃饭吗
So do we eat together in the cafeteria from now on
还是有什么别的规矩
or how does that work?
你知道这里不是高中吧
You know this isn't high school, right?
我当然知道
Yeah, of course I know that.
但你还是会参加运动会的对吧
You are going to the pep rally, though, right?
说真的  迈克  加洛不会放过你的
Seriously, Mike, Gallo's not going to forget about you,
现在连我也算上了  也就是说
and now me, which means--
我们需要互相照应
We need to have each other's backs.
没错  所以现在开始我们不仅要一起吃饭
Exactly. So from now on, we don't just eat together,
还要尽可能的多呆在一起
we stick together as much as possible.
唯一比较难做到这一点的时间
The only time I see that being a problem
应该是下午两点到四点
is afternoons between 2:00 and 4:00.
我要在厨房工作
I took a job working in the kitchen.
那从今天开始  下午两点到四点的时间
Then starting from today, I'm gonna be doing something
我会尽量待在公共场合
very public from 2:00 to 4:00.
罗斯  你跟我来
Ross, you're coming with me.
怎么了  有什么事吗
Why, is there a problem?
不能说
That's not for me to say.
那我们要去哪
Well, where are we going?
心理咨询师要见你
The counselor wants to see you.
但我们正要去吃早餐呢伙计
Yeah, we're on our way to breakfast, man.
那你就给他留块饼干吧
Well, then you can save him a biscuit,
但他一定得跟我走
but he's coming with me.
走吧
Let's go.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我听说了你的事
I heard what happened.
所以你也知道杰西卡在犯浑了吗
So you know that Jessica was being an asshole?
我听说的是你见了五个租客
What I heard was that you interviewed five tenants,
然后找到了各种理由把他们拒绝了
and you found a way to turn them all down.
所以你不想说说到底怎么了吗
So why don't you tell me what the hell's going on?
一切都不好了
Everything's going on.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
唐娜  这些租客在租办公室的时候
Donna, nobody's gonna be taking these offices
都会要这些大办公室
without taking the bullpen.
这是这块地方的灵魂所在
It's the heart and soul of this space.
这也是你的灵魂所在
And it's also the heart and soul of you.
正是  所以我不能容忍
Exactly, which is why I will not stand
另一个律所跑来用他们鱼龙混杂的小职员
for another firm to stick their promiscuous associates
玷污我纯洁的孵化间
in my innocent incubator.
好吧  我选择不回应这句  我只有一句话
Okay, I'm gonna choose not to respond to that except to say,
你有没有想过可以不出租办公室呢
did it ever occur to you to rent to someone without the bullpen?
唐娜  那不可能
Donna, that's never gonna happen.
可能
It could.
你只找了律师事务所
You've only been looking at law firms
而律所需要公共空间  但是...
and law firms need communal spaces, but--
其他公司则不需要  天呐
Other firms don't. Oh, my God.
我怎么就没想到
Why didn't I think of that?
我们可以做高净值人士的财务规划师
We can go with financial planners for high net worth individuals.
没错  他们很老派
That's it. They're old school.
他们的对话都很有教养
They have privileged conversations.
他们都是软蛋
They're pussies.
这句我也不回应了
Again, I'm not gonna engage.
最棒的一点在于他们都不精通法律
And best of all they're not legally savvy,
所以我可以把任何我想要的细则塞给他们
and I can shove any fine print down their throats that I want.
唐娜  你真是个天才
Donna, you're a genius.
我现在只需确保你不会再次搞砸面谈了
The only thing left for me to do is make sure you don't shit the bed in another interview.
你为什么觉得我就会搞砸
What makes you think I would do that?
根据我们的每一次对话  包括这一次
Every conversation we've ever had, including this one.
有理有据  去张罗吧
Fair point. Set it up.
你找我
You wanted to see me?
没错  也许你可以解释一下
Yes, and maybe you can explain
你为什么至今没有来找我
why you haven't come to see me yet.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我在说弗兰克・加洛
I'm talking about the fact that Frank Gallo
在公共区域对你亮刀子了
pulled a knife on you in the common area.
听着  我谢谢你的关心  但我没事
Look, I appreciate your concern, but I'm fine.
没事
Fine?
迈克  你该庆幸他没有把你千刀万剐了
Mike, you are lucky he didn't cut you into a million pieces.
找不找你又有什么区别呢
What difference does it make?
我没来找你是因为你也无能为力
I didn't come to you because there's nothing you can do about it.
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help you.
没错  但你帮不了  不是吗
Yeah, but you can't, can you?
我告诉过你加洛买通了狱警了
Look, I already told you Gallo has guards in his pockets,
然后你告诉我你无权管理狱警
and you told me you have no authority over the guards.
那你可以提出正式的指控
Then file a formal allegation.
我不可能那样做
No way I am doing that.
听我说  你已经和这人起过两次冲突了
Listen to me, you have had two incidents with this man.
假如记录下来的话  就会有人来调查
Now, if it goes on record, it triggers an investigation.
然后这个地方的每个狱警和犯人
And then every single guard and inmate
都会知道我做过什么了
in this place will know what I did.
你是情愿在这里空做假设
And would you rather have a hypothetical problem
还是想处理你所面临的真正的
or deal with your real problem
不会自动消失的问题
that isn't going away by itself?
我想要的是不必在这两者间做出选择
What I'd like is to not have to choose either one.
你不知道我告诉你  兄弟
Well, I've got news for you, bro.
不管怎样
One way or another,
无论你喜不喜欢  你都必须做出选择
you're making that choice whether you like it or not.
你看起来没事
Well, you seem to be okay.
看来之前不是加洛在玩什么花招
I'm guessing that wasn't some trick by Gallo
想把我们分开
to split us up before?
嗯  不是
No, it wasn't.
那跟我说说那个心理咨询师想干什么
Then how about you tell me what that counselor wanted?
那不重要
It's not important.
我之前说我们不能抛下对方
Hey, when I said we can't leave each other alone,
其中也包括要信息共享
I meant information too,
他是不会无缘无故早上一起来就拦下你的
and he's not yanking you down there first thing in the morning for nothing.
这不重要  是因为我不会按他的意思做
It's not important because what he wanted, I'm not doing.
我明白了
I get it.
他想要你举报加洛  而你不信任我
He wanted you to inform on Gallo, and you don't trust me.
我不是不信任你
That's not true,
但我不准备做的事不必告诉你吧
but I don't have to tell you about every offer I get that I don't take.
对  没问题
Yeah, that's fine,
但我需要你明白他要你做的是什么
but I need you to understand what he's asking you to do,
因为假如你举报了加洛
because if you rat on Gallo,
这里就会只剩我一个人了
I'm gonna be left here by myself.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
我是指马克・辛吉斯
I'm talking about Mark Higgins.
我最初来这里时他是我的室友
He was my roommate when I first got here.
他被另外某个混蛋骚扰了
He was being harassed by some different asshole,
一周要挨打几次
taking a beating a couple times a week,
然后那个心理咨询师  朱利叶斯
and that counselor, Julius,
说服他去举报
convinced him to go on record.
两周后  他们直接把他打昏迷了
Two weeks later, they put him in a coma.
然后就再也没醒过来
He never came out.
所以你的意思是我不能相信朱利叶斯
So you're telling me that I can't trust Julius?
我只是说马克相信了他
I'm saying Mark did,
然后马克就不在这里了
and Mark's not here anymore.
哈维  你去哪了  杰西卡需要...
Harvey, where have you been? Jessica needs--
迈克・罗斯  初级合伙人
唐娜  我需要你给肖恩・卡荷尔打电话
Donna, I need you to get Sean Cahill on the phone,
立刻马上
and I need it yesterday.
我知道你在担心迈克
I know you're worried about Mike,
但你总得让人家做事吧
but let the man do his job.
我不是不让他做事
I'm not stopping him from doing his job.
我是想让他做快点
I'm telling him to do it faster.
你想要我怎么做  哈维
What do you want me to do, Harvey?
我已经给他留了一堆言了...
I've left him a dozen messages--
那就再给他留一堆  与此同时
Then leave him a dozen more, and while you're at it,
在他给你回电前都不要离开你的位置
don't leave your desk until he calls back.
-我做不到  -为什么
- I can't do that. - Why the hell not?
因为我得确保路易今天不会再赶走租客了
Because I'm making sure that Louis doesn't blow it with another tenant today.
那就让瑞秋去做
Then get Rachel to do that.
哈维  瑞秋要上法学院
Harvey, Rachel has law school.
再说了  我也想做这件事
And besides that, this is something that I want to do.
唐娜  我不在乎路易和他的租客
Donna, I don't give a shit about Louis and his tenants.
可我在乎
Well, I do.
因为我们都说过我们会尽一切努力
Because we all said that we would give everything we had
带这里重回昔日盛景
to get this place back to where it was,
而此时此刻
and right now,
杰西卡正带着一个策划在会议室等你
Jessica has a prospect waiting for you in the conference room.
所以与其责备我和肖恩在花时间做事
So instead of coming down on me and Sean for doing our jobs,
你不如到会议室去做好你该做的
why don't you get over there and do yours?
原告确认了被告的身份  法官
The plaintiff ID'd the defendant, Your Honor.
这是一个一目了然的案子
It's an open and shut case.
并不尽然
No, it isn't,
因为我们不能忽视他作为证人的可信度
because his reliability as a witness can't be ignored.
你这是什么意思  他的视力很好
What are you talking about? His eyes work perfectly.
没错  他的嘴巴也同样厉害
Yes, and so does his mouth,
因为记录上显示
because as the record shows,
他有为了谋取和解而做虚假陈述的历史
he has a history of making false statements to extort settlements.
你不觉得这有点讽刺吗
Don't you think it's a little ironic,
你居然在伦理课上质疑别人的品格
you questioning someone's character in an ethics class?
你这么说是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我想庭上知道那是什么意思
I think the court knows what it means.
但我认为  如果你想
And what I think is if you're trying
通过贬低我来得分
to disparage me to score some points,
那你至少应该有胆量明说出来
then you should have the guts to say what you mean.
所以  娜奥米  为什么我说出来就很讽刺
So, Naomi, how is it ironic coming from me?
好了  大家  我们暂停一下吧
Okay, everyone, why don't we take a quick break?
因为你未婚夫正因诈骗罪入狱两年
It's ironic because your fiancé
所以你说出来很讽刺
is currently serving a two-year sentence for fraud,
不论你怎么说  大家都知道你知情
and no matter what you say, everyone here knows you knew.
好了  今天就到这里
All right, that's enough for today.
但是  娜奥米  你要知道在陪审团眼中
But, Naomi, if you're gonna impugn another lawyer's character,
指摘对方律师的人品的律师
you should know that in the eyes of a jury,
也不是什么有人品的律师
it doesn't say great things about your own.
瑞秋  我能跟你谈谈吗
Rachel, can I speak to you for a minute?
不好意思  教授  我五分钟后有一门课
I'm sorry, professor, I have another class in five minutes.
有人说为求胜利就要不眠不休  并非如此
They say coffee's for closers, but it's not.
真的吗
Is that a fact?
真的  所以我两年前就戒了咖啡
Yeah, which is why I gave it up two years ago,
那东西害死人
because that shit'll kill you.
挑衅证监会也害死人
So will playing chicken with the SEC,
但你好像也没在乎啊
but you don't seem to have a problem with that.
你知道我是谁
You know who I am.
我还知道你即将面临指控
I also know you have an indictment on the horizon,
并在找新的律师
and you're looking for new representation
因为没有任何脑经正常的律师
because no lawyer in his right mind
会愿意沾上你
wants to touch you with a ten-foot pole.
如果你是这样跟大客户说话的
If that's how you talk to prospective clients,
那我对你也没什么兴趣了
maybe I don't want to get to know you better.
我觉得你有  因为你也找不到别人了
I think you do because you got nowhere else to go.
问题是  你为什么会认为我就会代理你
The question is, what makes you think I'd take you on?
天呐  我不知道
Gee, I don't know.
你怎么不问问你们那忙忙碌碌的
Why don't we ask one of the hundreds of associates
几百个律师呢
you have walking around here?
不对  你们这儿已经没有律师了
Oh, wait, you don't have any associates walking around here.
我理解了  你觉得我们现在绝望了
I get it -- you think we're down and desperate.
不  我认为你们挑衅律师协会
No, I think you played chicken with the ABA,
结果栽了跟头
came up short,
而现在你们需要一个高调的客户和一场大胜
and now you need a high-profile client and a big, goddamn win
否则不用多久你们就要流落街头了
or you're gonna be on the street in about ten minutes.
我需要的是立马把你从这里赶出去
What I need is to kick your ass out of here right the hell now
因为我对你这种客户不感兴趣
because I'm not interested in your kind of client.
好了  不开玩笑了
All right, fun time's over.
我会付一笔定金并给你三倍的价格
I'll pay you a retainer and triple your rate.
你就是付我五倍的价格
You can quintuple my rate.
我的答案也不会变
My answer's never gonna change.
听我说  我们这是完美合作
Listen to me. We are a perfect fit.
我需要  你也需要
I need this and you do too.
成功的话  我的生意在我有生之年都给你们
And it works out, my business is your firm's the rest of my life.
这正是我不想跟你合作的原因
That's exactly why I don't want it.
如果你不介意的话  我要享受我的咖啡了
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm gonna enjoy my coffee.
我应该祝你在证监会好运  威廉
I'd wish you luck with your SEC troubles, William,
但就算说了也不是真心的
but I wouldn't mean it.
他人呢
Where is he?
他不在这里
He's not here.
什么叫他不在这里
What do you mean he's not here?
他去行使宪法第四章15节的权力了
I mean he's taking his 4:15 constitutional.
你是说他去厕所了
You mean he's in the bathroom.
我想应该是的
I believe that's the situation,
但是我更乐意告诉自己他出去散步了
but I prefer to tell myself he's out for a stroll.
我感觉自己重生了
I feel like a new man.
好像肩膀卸掉了一百磅的重量
Like a 100-pound load off my shoulders.
我想我们都知道那重量不是从肩膀上卸下的
I think we all know that's not where it came from.
真有趣  来吧  路易
Well, that was fun. Come on, Louis.
我们还有些会议要约呢
We've got some appointments to make.
不用了  我搞定了
No need. I took care of it.
-什么  -你以为我卸下的是什么重担
- What? - What do you think I meant by a load off my shoulders?
我签了新租客了
I signed the new tenant.
你自己签的
Without me?
对  我找到一个和善的老人
Well, yes. Listen, I found this sweet old man
他管着一些友好的基金经理
who runs a bunch of friendly money managers
打算扩大规模
looking to expand,
他们都看着像有一千岁了
and they're all, like, 1,000 years old.
他们甚至都不需要大办公室
They're not even gonna need the bullpen,
他们明天搬过来  一切都会很完美
and they start tomorrow, and it's gonna be perfect.
不  路易  不会完美的
No, Louis, it's not going to be perfect.
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
我们说好了要一起解决这件事
We said we were gonna do this together,
我跟你一样是这个公司的一员
and I am a part of this firm as much as you are,
而当你这样不叫我就
and when you go ahead and you do something like this
单独行动  真的很让我生气
without me, it really pisses me off.
唐娜  对不起
Donna, I'm sorry.
我只是想向自己证明我不会搞砸
I just wanted to prove to myself that I could not screw this up.
那你搞砸的时候也别跑来找我
Well, don't come running to me when you do.
求求你告诉我
Oh, please tell me
你在做普通的土豆泥
you're making just plain old mashed potatoes.
我受够了他们一直给我们吃的
I am getting so sick of that au gratin bullshit
那些裹面包屑的垃圾
they keep serving us.
你怎么不去跟厨师说呢
Why don't you take it up with the cook?
那我就是想跟你反映怎么办
Well, what if I want to take it up with you?
那我就只能说你运气不好了
Well, I'd say you're shit out of luck
因为这不是我能决定的
because it is not my call.
事实上  我觉得能找到落单的你
Actually, I feel hip deep in luck
我是走了好运才对
finding you here all by yourself.
你不会在这里对我做什么的
You're not gonna do anything to me here.
这里闲杂人等太多
There's too many other people.
你知道  我刚来的时候
You know, when I first got here,
还没有高中毕业证
I didn't have a high school diploma.
真没想到
Surprise, surprise.
不知不觉我已经跟你一样是一个书呆子了
Before you know it I was a regular Poindexter just like you.
恭喜  你父母肯定很骄傲
Congratulations. Your parents must be so proud.
没错
They are.
我喜欢所有的科目  但最喜欢的是数学
I loved all my subjects, but math was my favorite,
尤其喜欢数学的传递属性
transitive property in particular.
加洛  我们讨论过这个话题了
Gallo, we've been over this.
你要通过我戳到哈维的点
You're gonna get to Harvey through me.
谢谢你  我知道了
Thank you. Got it.
没错  不过这才刚开始
That's true, but that's just the beginning,
因为如果我能通过你戳到哈维的点
because if I can get to Harvey through you,
也就是说我也能通过别人戳到你的点
that must mean I can get to you through somebody else.
你离凯文远点
You leave Kevin out of this.
现在有点晚了  迈克
A little late for that, Mike.
在这里我们实行狱友制
See, in here we use the buddy system.
可你让你的狱友落单了
You left your buddy alone.
你干了什么
What the hell did you do?
你自己去瞅瞅呗
Why don't you find out for yourself?
他在厕所  我建议你动作快点
He's in the bathroom. I'd hurry if I were you.
他坚持不了多久了
He's not gonna be conscious much longer.
凯文
Kevin.
发生了什么
Hey, what happened?
我很想说对方比我还惨
I'd say you should see the other guy, Mike,
但是对方有三个人我也没辙
but there were three of them.
来  起来
Oh, come on, hey, get up.
你不是说要待在公共场合的吗
I thought you said you were gonna stay in the open.
人有三急
Everyone needs to go to the bathroom,
加洛和他的狱友已经恭候多时了
and Gallo and his buddies were waiting for me when I got here.
走  我带你去医务室
Come on, we got to get you to the infirmary.
-不行  -你需要医生给你看看
- No, no! We can't. - You need someone to look at you.
我们不能去
We can't!
这正是加洛希望的
That's exactly what Gallo wants.
因为如果我们去了医务室
Because if we go to the infirmary,
我们就必须要提交报告
we're gonna have to file a report.
没错  然后他就不用亲自动手了
Yeah, and then he won't have to lay a finger on us
因为别人会替他动手
because someone else will do it for him.
我们怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我们只能
The only thing we can do.
忍气吞声
Suck it up and take it
直到加洛自己换攻击目标
until Gallo gets someone else in his sights.
哥们  我不管那些傻逼说了什么
Dude, I don't give a shit what those douches say.
那些股票都不值他们的那堆卫生巾
Those shares aren't worth the tampons they're printed on.
几楼
what floor?
告诉他们把那玩意塞屁眼里吧
Tell them to stick it in their ass.
我在打电话  哥们
I'm on the phone, guy.
我知道  但是...
I know. I understand that, but--
皮-斯-利律所  你和我们公司有什么业务
Pearson Specter Litt. What business do you have with our--
天哪  玩蛋去吧
Oh, Jesus Christ. Lick my balls.
你刚才对我说了什么
What did you just say to me?
等等  火箭车
Hold on, Skidmarks.
[西班牙语]我打电话呢  哥们  懂不
En el telefono, hombre. Comprende?
好了  兄弟  我得挂了
All right, man, I got to jet.
我们今天搬到新地方了
We're settling into our new digs today.
回头再聊  扫把星
All right, later, Brosef Stalin.
对不起
Excuse me.
我无意偷听
I couldn't help but overhear.
但这里肯定是有什么误会
There must be some mistake.
我们是租给了史蒂芬投资集团的
We're leasing space to the satellite division
卫星部门
of the Stevens Investment Group.
就是我  斯图・布齐尼  我管卫星部门
That's me, pal, Stu Buzzini. I run the satellite division.
我见你老板的时候可不是这么说的
Well, that wasn't made clear to me when I met your boss.
那个老家伙
Old man river?
他不会天天来的
He's not gonna drag his ass in here every day.
他都快要见上帝了
He's got one foot in the grave.
那他给你看租赁合同了吗
Well, then, did he share with you the lease agreement?
因为上面写明了着装规定
Because it clearly outlined a dress code.
你以为我穿这个工作
You think I wear this to work?
你以为我是猪吗
What am I, an asshole?
你再见到我  我就穿西装了
Next time you see me I'll be in a suit
而且价钱是你这套的三倍多
three times more expensive than yours.
-这是布莱奥尼  -我看这是屎莱奥尼
- This is a Brioni. - It's a Bri-shitty, as far as I'm concerned.
来吧  哥们  碰一个
Come on, buddy, give me some.
拜托兄弟  别让我一人举着
Come on, brah, don't leave me hanging.
-什么  我不... -这才是我的姑娘
- Wha--I don't-- - Bssh. That's my girl.
我开玩笑的
I'm just kidding, Sally.
有问题就找我  好吗
holler at me if you need anything, okay?
我期待着我们成为损友
I'm looking forward to being douche-mates.
搅屎棍  昨晚拿到那个姑娘的电话了
Shit Stick, huh, you get that girl's number last night?
这就对了
That's right.
大蛋蛋  你怎么找到我们的
Ball Sack, how did you track us down, man?
我们不是把你开除了吗
I thought we fired you.
我了个去  我干了些什么
Holy goddamn shit, what have I done?
走  兄弟们  捞钱去
Come on, boys, let's make some money!
-唐娜  听我说  -我知道
- Donna, listen to me. - I know.
那你知道我...
Then you know that I--
像以前一样搞了一团糟
Shit the bed like you never have before?
-我很...  -出糗了
- I am so-- - Banged the monkey?
搬起石头砸自己的脚了
Screwed the pooch?
-唐娜  拜托  -作茧自缚了
- Donna, please-- - Flinked the flank?
那是什么意思
What does flink the flank mean?
意思是我还没嘲笑够你
It means I'm not finished enjoying this.
你什么时候能结束
When do you think you'll be finished?
因为我想知道要怎么办
Because I need to know what to do.
我不知道  租期什么时候结束
I don't know. When does their lease expire?
天哪  我给他们了一个延期选择
Oh, my God, I cooked in an extension option!
路易  放心
Louis, relax.
最重要的是要记住
The important thing to remember here
这就是你不听我话的下场
is that this is your fault for not listening to me.
这有什么用
How does that help me?
对你没用  但对我有用
It doesn't. It helps me.
-唐娜  -好吧  听我说
- Donna! - Okay, listen to me.
如果你真的要我帮忙  我会帮你的
If you really want my help, I'm gonna give it to you.
在接下来的24小时的某一刻
What's gonna happen is,
会发生一件只会戳到你的点的
sometime in the next 24 hours, a minor incident
芝麻大的小事
that would mean nothing to anybody else but you
会让你想终止这场惨剧
is gonna make you want to undo this fiasco.
我现在就想终止
I want to undo it right now.
但我正在告诉你不能这么做
But I'm telling you not to
因为除了会雪上加霜以外
because in addition to making things worse,
杰西卡还会弄死你
Jessica will kill you.
所以就先等等看吧  然后在
So just wait things out and in another--
抱歉  他们的租约什么时候到期来着
I'm sorry, when does their lease expire again?
-还有18个月  -18个月之后
- 18 months. - 18 months...
这整件事就会成为一段逝去的遥远回忆了
this whole thing will be a distant memory.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
你能让它随风飘逝吗
Can you let it go?
是的  我觉得你可以
Yes, I think you can.
你能做到的
You can do it.
是的  我能
Yes, I can.
那就勇往直前去征服世界吧
Then go forth and conquer.
我估计他最多撑一个半小时
I'm gonna give him about an hour and a half.
杰西卡  有什么可以效劳的吗
Jessica, what can I do for you?
什么事让你这么开心
What are you so happy about?
我刚看到了我们的新租客
I just saw our new tenants.
一帮蠢货交易员
A bunch of dickhead traders.
他们会把路易逼疯的
They're gonna drive Louis crazy.
我刚接到一通非常有意思的电话
Well, I just got a very interesting phone call,
而我听了一点都笑不出来
but I'm not smiling about it.
尼日利亚王子把他的遗产留给了你吗
Nigerian prince leaving you his inheritance?
你不知道我告诉你  这是个骗局
Because I got news for you, it's a scam.
我也希望这是个骗局
I hope it's a scam
因为我刚听说你拒绝了一位
because I just heard you turned down a client
旗下投资机构价值20亿美元的客户
whose investment firm is worth $2 billion.
我才不在乎它们价值多少
Well, I don't give a shit how much they're worth.
我是不会为威廉・萨特辩护的
I'm not representing William Sutter.
是的  你会的
Oh, yes, you are,
除非你和我说清楚为什么不愿意这么做
or you're gonna give me a hell of a reason why not.
你想知道原因吗
You want the reason?
和这家伙比起来麦道夫和傅滋曼就跟圣徒一样
This guy makes Madoff and Forstman look like saints,
而我绝不要再和另一位罪犯产生联系
and I'm not getting involved with another criminal.
哈维  我觉得你不明白这里现在的状况
Harvey, I don't think you understand what's going on here.
我们现在用转租的租户来填满这些办公室
We're filling up these offices with subletters
好让外人看起来我们还在正常运作
to make it look like we're still alive,
但如果我们再不找到一个新客户
but if we don't land a new client
来告诉全世界我们王者归来了
and show the world that we're back,
那还不如直接把地方卖给他们算了
then we may as well let them have the space for good.
那你让我找找别人
Then let me land someone else.
最好是个大客户
Well, then it better be someone huge,
而且你最好在48小时内找到
and you better do it in the next 48 hours
因为那是我约萨特下一次会面的时间
because that's when I set our next appointment with Sutter,
那时你要还没找到  我们就把萨特签下来
and when we get there, we're signing him as a client.
你知道该去找谁  对不对
You know who you have to go to, right?
唐娜  没可能  他不行
Donna, no way. Not him.
哈维  你听到杰西卡说的话了
Harvey, you heard Jessica.
我们现在处境艰难  你也清楚
We're in trouble, and you know it,
而且南森・巴恩斯不是个罪犯
and Nathan Burns isn't a criminal.
他只是个混蛋而已
He's just an asshole.
一个我说过绝对不会与之合作的混蛋
An asshole I told I'd never get into business with.
那可真是太糟了
Well, that's too bad
因为我看到杰西卡往你办公室
because I set up a meeting with him
走的时候就立马帮你约了和他会面
the second I saw Jessica heading for your office.
迈克  我现在不方便跟你谈话
Mike, I can't talk right now.
有位犯人大约5分钟内会过来见我
I have an inmate coming in in about five minutes.
很好  因为我这些话大概只需要5秒钟
Good, because this will take about five seconds.
你得把加洛弄到别的关押区去
You need to get Gallo transferred to another block,
而且你必须立刻就做
and you need to do it right now.
先冷静一下  告诉我发生了什么事
Calm down and tell me what happened.
我很冷静
I am calm.
他在我工作时袭击了我的狱友
He attacked my cellmate while I was working.
这是间巨大的监狱
Now, this is a huge prison.
你把他给我弄走
You get him goddamn moved.
我没有这么做的权限
I don't have the authority to do that.
这是本周第二次你在告诉我
That's the second time this week you told me
你可以帮我后又和我说你不能帮我了
you can't help me after telling me you can help me.
-迈克  听着  -还有别再叫我
- Mike, listen-- - And don't tell me
提出正式指控了
to make a formal allegation again
因为那么做只会让事情变得更糟
because that is just going to make this worse.
没必要非得这样
It doesn't have to.
你是不是也这么告诉马克・辛吉斯的
Is that what you told Mark Higgins?
你这样就太过分了
That's out of line.
你怎么敢问我和其他犯人
How dare you ask me about discussions
之间讨论的谈话内容
I've had with another inmate.
据我所知
From what I understand,
他已经没法再和任何人讨论和谈话了
he can't have discussions with anyone anymore.
我也不想听他出了什么事
And I don't want to hear what happened to him.
我只想弄明白如何才能活着从这里出去
I just want to figure out how to get out of here alive.
如果你一直这么跟我说话
Well, I can't help you do that
我也没法帮你
if you keep talking to me like that.
听我说  朱利叶斯  我很抱歉
Listen to me, Julius, I'm sorry,
但我不能告发加洛
but I cannot tell on Gallo.
所以如果你没法把他转移走的话
So if you can't get him moved,
我得辞去我现在的工作
I need to quit my job,
因为凯文是我在这里唯一的朋友
because Kevin is my only friend in here.
我工作的话他一天就有两小时落单
That's two hours a day that he's exposed.
我不会再丢下他一个人了
I'm not gonna leave him alone again.
迈克  我很不想一直拒绝你
Mike, I hate to keep telling you no,
但在这里事情不是这么运作的
but that's not how it works in here.
什么不是这么运作的
How what works in here?
你不能随随便便就辞职
You can't just walk away from a job,
而且在这件事情上我也无能为力
and there's nothing I can do about that.
哈维・斯佩克特  真是没想到
Harvey Specter, as I live and breathe.
很高兴见到你  南森
Good to see you, Nathan.
不  并不高兴
No, it's not.
我一直在想在你的律师们都离开之后
I was wondering how long it would take after your lawyers left
要多久你才会来求我救你于水火之中
before you came here begging me to take you on.
我看起来像是过来求你的吗
Do I look like I'm begging?
实话说
To tell you the truth,
我以为你能撑到下周呢
I didn't expect you until next week.
绝望真是个好东西
You know, desperation's a beautiful thing.
好吧  你说得对
Okay, you got me.
那你是想一直这么拿这事恶心我呢
The question is, do you want to keep sticking it to me
还是要接受我这个仅此一次的提案
or do you want to take my one-time-only offer
成为我的头号客户
to become my number one client?
好吧  哈维  我也不想再给你添堵了
Okay, Harvey, I'm done sticking it to you,
如果你想拿到我这个客户  就得争取
if you want my business, you'll have to earn it.
不然你认为这些尼克斯前排票是来干嘛的
What do you think these front row Knicks tickets are for?
很好  我会给我的继子
Great. I'll give them to my stepson
因为他蠢得没边都不知道尼克斯烂死了
because he's too stupid to know the Knicks suck.
-你到底想要什么  纳森  -洛克伍德能源公司
- What do you want, Nathan? - Lockwood Energy.
他们十年来一直都是我的眼中钉
They've been a pain in my ass for ten years.
现在他们竟然想把生意做进我的后院
Now they're trying to bring their business to my backyard.
你想让我阻止他们
And you want me to block them?
我想让你拿着一堆的限制令塞进他们的菊花
I want you to shove so many restraining orders up their ass
让他们痛到无法呼吸
they can't even breathe,
而且我希望你能在今晚我们在本身餐厅
and I want it done by the time we sit down
吃开胃菜前  就搞定它
for appetizers tonight at Per Se.
那下次你见到我时
Then the next time you see me,
他们就会变得像你后视镜里的一小颗污点一样
they'll be a speck in your rear view mirror.
不过纳森  当我到餐厅的时候
But, Nathan, when I get there,
你最好手里拿着一杯威士忌等着我
you better have a Scotch waiting for me.
你打电话预定餐位时
You can order one for both of us
可以帮我们两人都预定一杯
when you call and make the reservations.
晚上八点  准时到
8 P.M. Sharp.
还有  哈维
and Harvey?
如果你不打电话亲自预定  我会知道的
If you don't call yourself, I'll know.
你真是个混蛋  纳森
You really are a dick, Nathan.
我是没错  但凡是我许下的承诺
I am, but when I give my word,
我决不食言
the world knows that it's rock solid.
所以  记得准时到
So, be there on time,
把事情办好
get that shit done,
不然就别露面了
or don't bother showing up at all.
西梅汁啊西梅汁啊  你真甜
Prune juice, prune juice you are so sweet
我全心全意爱着你
I love you all the way from my head down to my--
该死的
Goddamn it!
伙计  你能帮我做什么
Hey, guy, what can you do for me?
我的名字不是伙计  是路易
The name isn't Guy, it's Louis,
我在冰箱里放了
and I had a two-gallon bottle of
两加仑的西梅汁
prune juice in the refrigerator.
我想知道它去哪了
I want to know where it went.
没问题  我把那玩意扔掉了
No problem. I had to toss that shit.
你扔掉了我的西梅汁
You threw away my prune juice?
让我这样说吧
Let me put it this way,
如果我的菊花里再长一个菊花
if my asshole had an asshole,
那它闻起来就和你那瓶玩意一样
that's what it would smell like.
西梅汁就是这种味道
That's what it's supposed to smell like.
放轻松  哥们  不就是一瓶西梅汁嘛
Take it easy, bro, it's just prune juice.
不  这不仅仅是西梅汁的问题
No, it isn't just prune juice.
这事关我的厨房的神圣性
It's the sanctity of my kitchen.
除了我的西梅汁外
And on top of my prune juice,
你还吃光了我所有的麦麸棒
you ate all of my bran bars.
你一定严重便秘吧
You must spend a lot of time on the shitter.
这和这次谈话没有关系
That's neither here nor there.
你违反了租约里的第三章C条款
You, sir, are in violation of subsection 3-C of your lease,
这意味着如果你再侵犯我的厨房
which means if it happens again,
你就可以滚蛋了
you're out on your ass.
什么
What?
什么样的混蛋才会把麦麸棒和西梅汁
What kind of dildo puts bran bars and prune juice
放进租赁合同里
in a lease agreement?
这个混蛋  就是站在这里的混蛋
This dildo. This dildo right here.
你疯了吗
Are you nuts?
不  我会成为你最怕的噩梦
No. I'm your worst nightmare,
因为我这个生气到颤抖的混蛋绝不会罢休
because this quivering angry dildo isn't going away
直到我满意为止
until it gets its satisfaction.
你刚刚和我说了什么
What did you just say to me?
我刚刚说
I just said,
如我再发现你违反了租赁合同
this dildo is gonna be in your face slapping it around,
我就会狠狠地扇着你的小脸
then up your ass marching you right out the door
然后拎着你的屁股让你滚出公司
if it catches you in violation of your lease ever again.
你好
Hello?
瑞秋  我是邓巴教授
Rachel, it's Professor Dunbar.
有什么能帮您的吗  教授
How can I help you, Professor?
我本想在课堂结束之后找你谈这件事
I tried to talk to you about this after class,
但我在想你是否对
but I was wondering if you'd be interested in helping me
帮我做一件我一直很关心的事
with something that's near and dear to my heart.
-什么事  -无罪计划
- What's that? - The Innocence Project.
你想让我帮你让无辜的人摆脱死刑
You want me to help you get an innocent man off death row?
这正是我想要的
That's exactly what I want.
这不会和今天在课上
This wouldn't have anything to do with the incident
发生的小插曲有关吧
after class the other day, would it?
你为什么这么说
What makes you say that?
因为我没有精力同时去应付两件事
Because I can't do both of these things at the same time,
你知道的
and you know it.
没错
Okay, yes.
我想你可能需要一些方式来缓解
Yes, I thought you might need a little relief,
但如果我觉得你不能胜任
but I wouldn't be offering you this
我是不会向你提出的
if I didn't think you'd earned it.
非常感谢  教授  只是
I appreciate that, Professor, just...
我不会就此退缩的
I'm not one to back away from a fight.
瑞秋  我不是要你退缩
Rachel, I'm not asking you to back away from a fight.
我是想让你专注于做更重要的事
I'm asking you to pick one that's more important.
-怎么样  -什么怎么样
- Well? - Well, what?
你乖乖地去打给本身餐厅预约了吗
Did you grovel to Per Se to get yourself a reservation?
我没有乖乖地去打给本身餐厅
I didn't grovel to Per Se.
我乖乖地去找纳森了
I groveled to Nathan.
但我不想聊我都做了什么
But I don't want to talk about what I did.
我想聊聊你做了什么
I want to talk about what you did,
因为如果你没有提交动议
because if you didn't file those motions
那么我就可以直接取消晚餐预约了
then I might as well cancel dinner.
我不仅提交动议了
I didn't just get them filed,
我还让市检察官把这些动议放在了最前面
I got the city attorney to put them on the top of the pile.
限制令  专利侵权诉讼
Restraining order, patent infringement suit,
侵权干扰和环境危害报告
tortious interference, and environmental hazard report.
洛克伍德会被打懵圈的
Lockwood isn't gonna know what hit them.
好吧  与其在这里洋洋得意
Well, instead of patting yourself on the back,
为什么你不拿起电话让肖恩・卡荷尔来见我
why don't you pick up the phone and get me Sean Cahill?
她不需要打给肖恩・卡荷尔
she doesn't have to get you Sean Cahill,
因为他就站在你面前
'cause he's standing right in front of ya.
你终于来了
It's about time.
为什么你不回我的电话
Why the hell haven't you returned any of my phone calls?
哈维  我需要你坐下
Harvey, I need you to sit down.
肖恩  为什么拖这么久
Sean, what took so long?
我花了好长时间才发现
It took me so long to find out
弗兰克・加洛哪也不会去
that Frank Gallo's not going anywhere
因为上面有人
because he's got people up in high places
在罩着他
who are protecting him.
告诉是谁在罩着他  我来搞定他们
Then tell me who they are. I'll put them in the ground.
-没那么容易  -对我来说很容易
- Look, it's not that simple. - It is to me.
哈维  你也许不明白
Harvey, you don't understand.
我知道除非他是政府的线人
I understand that unless he's a government informant,
我们就肯定能把他赶回原来的监狱去
we can get a criminal put back where he belongs.
你肯定是在逗我
You got to be kidding me.
我不能泄露联邦调查的内幕
Look, I can't reveal details of a federal investigation.
你无需泄露  我已经知道了
You don't have to. You just did.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我要去告诉迈克这是怎么回事
I'm telling Mike what the hell's going on.
站住  听我说
Stop. Just listen to me.
不能让别人知道这消息是我泄露的
No one can know that this came from me.
肯定不会有人知道...
No one's gonna know about it at all...
除了迈克
except Mike.
哈维  如果你现在去监狱
Harvey, if you go to that prison now,
你肯定来不及赶回来
you'll never make it back in time
和纳森吃晚饭了
for your dinner with Nathan.
唐娜  我不管你用什么办法
Donna, I don't care what you have to do.
告诉他我会晚到一小时
Get him a message that I'll be an hour late,
并要保证他能同意
and make sure he says it's okay.
-哈维  -搞定这件事
- Harvey-- - Take care of it.
我不能让一无所知的迈克
I'm not leaving Mike alone in there another minute
一个人待在那
without knowing what's coming.
哈维
Harvey.
迈克
Mike.
希望你是带着搞定加洛的好消息来的
Please tell me you came here with good news about Gallo.
我是有消息  但不是好消息
I have news, but it isn't good.
该死
Oh, shit.
迈克  听我说
Mike, listen to me.
卡荷尔乐意帮忙  但他能力有限
Cahill wants to help, but his hands are tied.
这话是什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
加洛转到这来不是因为表现良好
Gallo's not here because of good behavior.
他来是因为他达成了协议
He's here because he cut a deal.
开什么玩笑  他是个线人
You got to be kidding me. He's a goddamn informant?
是的
Yeah.
这下好了  他不会离开这里了
Oh, that's great. So he's not going anywhere,
我也走不了了  除非是死了被人抬出去
and neither am I unless it's in a goddamn body bag!
迈克  我会再想别的办法
Mike, I'm gonna find another way.
谢谢你  哈维
I'd appreciate that, Harvey,
但眼下我该怎么办
but what the hell am I supposed to do in the meantime?
你一开始根本不想
You didn't even want me to try
让我插手把他弄走
and get him out in the first place.
可一开始我也没让你
And I sure as hell didn't ask you
把他弄进监狱啊
to put him in here in the first place.
你还建议我跟人拉帮结伙
And all the advice you gave me to stay in a group did
可到头来我在这监狱里唯一的朋友
was get the only friend I have in here
被人揍得差点送进医院
nearly put in the hospital.
我现在只剩下唯一一个办法了
Look, there's only one other thing I can think of,
但你一定要妥善处理
but you'll have to play it just right
不然情况就会变得更糟
or we're gonna make things worse.
那就告诉我吧
Well, you might as well say it,
不过在我看来
because from where I'm standing,
不管你说不说  情况都好不到哪去
they are gonna get worse whether you tell me or not.
能跟你谈谈吗  路易
Louis, can I talk to you for a second?
这回怎么不喊"哥们"
What, no brah?
"蛋蛋"和"大鼻子"了
No scrotum? No dick nose?
不了  还是叫你路易好了
No, man, just plain old Louis.
我觉得我做人还算公平公正
Well, I consider myself a fair man.
你找我想谈什么
What exactly do you have to say?
我想说  你说的话我都明白了
I want to say I heard you before,
之前是我没有尊重你和你们的办公室
and I didn't treat you or your office with any respect,
所以我希望我们能重新开始
and I'm hoping we can have a fresh start.
很好
That's wonderful.
我很感动
I'm touched.
拿着这个滚吧
Now take this and get the hell out.
-这是什么  -驱逐令
- What's that? - It's an eviction notice.
我警告过你
I gave you a warning.
可你却搞砸了  所以现在该滚了
You screwed the pooch and now you're out.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
你冲我发火  我也道过歉了
You come at me, I apologize to you,
你却跟我玩这个
and then you do this?
我冲你发火和你跟我道歉这期间
Well, in between those two things,
你交易员们居然在
your traders were playing touch football
我爱惜的大办公室里玩橄榄球
in my beloved bullpen,
所以你的道歉我不接受
so I don't accept your bullshit apology.
你不能随便就把我们赶走
You won't get away with this.
已经赶了
I already did.
你真是个混蛋
You're a son of a bitch.
没错  我是个
Yeah, a son of a bitch who's got
对纽约地方法规烂熟于心的混蛋
the full weight of the New York City Legal Code on his side.
这就是给你上的第一课
And you just learned lesson number one.
千万别惹毛哈佛律师
Don't ever mess with a Harvard goddamn lawyer.
先生您好
Excuse me, sir?
不用紧张  我知道是哪个位置
Relax, I know where I'm going.
那是当然  但我觉得
I'm sure you do, but I don't think
您要找的人并不在那个座位上
you're going to find what you're looking for.
你说什么
What did you just say to me?
抱歉  有人告诉我在这个时间段
I'm sorry, but you match the description of a man
会有个和您长得差不多的人进来
I was told would be walking in here right about now.
他是怎么形容我的长相的
And what exactly is the description?
我还是不说为妙  但描述跟你丝毫不差
I'd rather not say, but it fit you to a T.
因此我敢确定
So I'm fairly confident you're the one
您就是本该和内森・伯恩斯共进晚餐的人
that was supposed to have dinner with Nathan Burns.
-说吧  -说什么
- Let's have it. - Have what?
他让你给我带的口信
The message you're supposed to give me.
他想对你说
He wanted me to tell you
你晚餐迟到让他受到了羞辱
that being late to dinner was a slap in the face,
让你带着你的提议见鬼去
and you could take your offer and shove it up your ass.
该死的  唐娜  我不是说让你联系内森
Goddamn it, Donna, I told you to call Nathan's office
告诉他我会晚到吗
and tell him I'd be late.
别来指责我  我联系过了
Don't "Goddamn it, Donna" me, I did call them.
可他没在餐厅
Well, he wasn't at the restaurant,
也就是说他没收到信息
so your message didn't get through.
我并没有给他留言  哈维
I didn't leave a message, Harvey.
我跟他的秘书联系的  我们认识十二年了
I spoke to his secretary who I've known for 12 years,
她说南森说没问题
and she said that Nathan said it was okay.
那不是他撒谎了就是秘书撒谎了
Then either he lied or she did,
但肯定不是他因为他可能是混蛋
and it wasn't him because he may be an asshole,
但是就像他说的那样  他说话算话
but as he likes to put it, his word is his bond.
除非有人改变了他的主意
Unless somebody changed his mind.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
唯一能给南森・巴恩斯这样的混蛋
The only person who has the power to put pressure
施加压力的人肯定是一个更混蛋的人
on an asshole like Nathan Burns is a bigger asshole,
再说你之前也说了  威廉・萨特会不择手段
and you said it yourself, William Sutter will do anything
得到他想要的东西
to get what he wants.
唐娜  我需要你联系戈德曼的比尔・约翰逊
Donna, I need you to get Bill Johnson at Goldman,
我要你现在就去
and I need you to do it right now.
-我不能  -为什么不能
- I can't. - Why the hell not?
因为他已经不在那里工作了
Because he doesn't work there anymore.
-该死  -哈维
- Oh, shit. - Harvey.
唐娜  我需要有人能告诉我
Donna, I need somebody who can tell me
萨特是否在买进股票
if Sutter's buying shares,
我需要在明天股市开盘之前知道
and I need it before the market opens tomorrow.
那路易刚把我们的办公室租给一群操盘手
Then it's a good thing Louis just rented our offices
倒是件好事了
to a bunch of traders.
杰西卡  太好了  你在
Oh, good, Jessica, you're here.
我要起草一些合同
I...I had a few contracts I need to file.
我需要你的签名
I just need your signature.
别以为我不知道过去五年
You think I don't know you've been
你一直在这些东西上伪造
forging my signature on shit like this
我的签名
for the last five years?
抱歉
I'm sorry...
你才不抱歉
No, you're not.
你也不需要抱歉
And you don't need to be.
你只是在给我节约时间而已
You were just trying to save me some time.
告诉我你来找我的真正目的吧
Now, why don't you tell me why you're really here?
这学期我在上应用伦理学
I... I'm taking a practical ethics course this semester.
我好久没读过那本书了
Well, it's been a long time since I read that textbook.
不是书的问题
My problem's not with the textbook.
是迈克
Mike.
一个同学为了赢我
One of my classmates stuck him in my face
在整个班面前攻击我
in front of the entire class to win an argument.
而你唯一想做的
And the only thing you want to
就是给她脸上来一拳吗
stick in her face is your fist?
差不多吧
Something like that.
然后教授给了我一个"无罪计划"项目
So the professor offered me an Innocence Project case,
我想要接受  但如果我接受了...
and I want to take it, but if I do...
其他的同学就会认为你怕她
The other students will think you're afraid of her.
对
Exactly.
那你就得让他们都怕你
Then you have to make all of them afraid of you.
然后他们对你的唯一印象就是
Then the only impression they'll have of you
你是一个惹不得的女人
is that you're one badass woman.
我怎么感觉你在法学院
Why do I get the feeling that when you were in law school
也经历过这种事
you went through something just like this?
瑞秋  我不知道你有没有注意到
Rachel, I don't know if you've been paying attention,
其实我每天都经历着这种事
but I go through something like this every damn day.
我想你就是负责的人吧
I take it you're the man in charge.
-你为什么这么觉得  -因为你还在这里
- What makes you think that? - Because you're still here,
而股市六个小时前就关闭了
and the markets closed six hours ago.
也许我正背着女朋友
Maybe I'm just here cheating on my girlfriend
和秘书偷情
with my secretary.
我说过了  你是负责的人
Like I said, you're the man in charge.
我喜欢你
I like you,
但你大老远跑到我的办公室肯定不只是
but you didn't come all the way down to my office
为了拍我马屁的吧  所以你何不直说呢
just to kiss my ass, so why don't you just get to it?
我需要知道谁买了这个公司5%的股份
I need to know who just bought 5% of this company.
恐怕我不能告诉你
Well, that's gonna be a problem
因为买的人  无论是谁  三个月内
because whoever it was doesn't have to file
都不用向证监会提交文件
with the SEC for three months.
你说得没错  我不是来拍你马屁的
You're right, I didn't come down here to kiss your ass,
但是我也不是来重上
but I didn't come for a refresher
证券法的
on securities law either.
我来是因为你这样的人可以帮我得到我想要的
I'm here because a guy like you can get me what I need.
我为什么要帮你
And why should I help you,
在我跪着求你的合伙人
when I went to your partner on my hands and knees
他仍然要撤我租的前提下
and I'm still gonna lose my lease
就因为我吃了他几个麦麸棒吗
because I ate a couple of goddamn bran bars?
在我看来  只要你给我我想要的
You give me what I need, as far as I'm concerned,
你就是把路易的麦麸棒都扔出去也没事
you can throw every bran bar Louis has off the roof.
我有人能够给你想要的信息
I got a guy that can get you that information.
不  不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
现在我知道了你的把柄
Now that I know you got something to lose,
我需要你做一点小投资
I need you to make a little investment.
你真的要为我搞你的合伙人吗
You serious about me sticking it to your partner?
你以为过去十年
What do you think I've been doing to him
我都在对他做些什么
for the last ten years?
准备好第二轮了吗
Are you ready for round two?
好了
I am.
其实  我想我已经赢了
In fact, I think I already won,
因为在一场辩论中
because one of the easiest things
最简单的事情就是攻击辩论者
to do in a debate is to attack the debater.
这是什么
What is this?
你能攻击我是因为我的未婚夫所做的事情
You went after me because of something that my fiancé did,
但其实  每个人都有见不得人的事
but the truth is, we all have skeletons in our closets.
而我和你的区别在于
The difference between you and me
我根本不屑利用这些东西
is that I don't care to use them.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我想你知道我想要什么
I think you know what I want.
我们开始吧
Shall we get started?
我想要就我对
I'd like to apologize
瑞秋・赞恩说过的话道歉
for saying what I said to Rachel Zane.
我这样做
I only did what I did
仅仅是因为她
because she's my
比我更聪明  比我更道德
intellectual and ethical superior.
我感觉很羞愧
I'm ashamed of myself,
这场比赛我主动认输
and I forfeit this competition.
你怎么做到让她这样的
How'd you get her to say that?
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
重要的是  现在大家都知道
What matters is, everyone here knows
我不害怕她了
that I'm not afraid of her.
那我想你是要留下了
I take it that means you're staying in the class then?
不
Nope.
这是我的正式退课申请
That is my official drop-out request.
我要接受"无罪计划"
I'm doing the Innocence Project.
你来干什么  哈维
What are you doing here, Harvey?
你都没有给我个机会让我向你展示
You didn't give me a chance to show you all the motions
我提交的那些动议  好帮你处理那个混蛋
I filed to keep that bastard out of your backyard.
因为我跟你说了  晚餐你要是迟到
Because I told you if you were late for dinner
那就自己玩去
you could go screw yourself.
不  你没给我一个展示的机会是因为
No, you didn't give me a chance to show you
你害怕威廉・萨特
because you're afraid of William Sutter,
但其实你该怕的人是我
when the person you should be afraid of is me.
你在说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
你以为我不知道
You think I don't know
他半夜买下了你的一部分股份
he bought a piece of you in the middle of the night,
现在正鼓动董事会开除你吗
and now he's pressuring the board to kick you out?
好吧
Okay, fine.
确实  我是鲸鱼  可他是鲨鱼
He did, but I'm a whale, and he's a shark,
我别无选择
and I have no other choice.
有件事我得告诉你  南森
I got a little news for you, Nathan.
我也有你公司的股份
I got a piece of your company too,
也就是说要么你雇我
which means you either hire me
我们一起对抗那个混蛋
and we fight that bastard together,
要么你跟他站一边  跟我对着干
or you go with him and you take me on.
不论如何
Either way,
这件事你都不可能全身而退
you're not walking out of this thing without a war.
我一直都是想合作的
All I ever wanted was to work together,
但我讨厌被威胁
but I do not like being bullied.
不  你是喜欢威胁别人  也正因为这个
No, you like to bully, which is exactly why
我才不愿意为你工作
I never wanted to represent you in the first place.
你来找我只是因为你需要我
You only came to me because you needed me.
你才不在乎我是什么样的人
You didn't care.
没错  南森  我是不在乎
You're right, Nathan, I didn't,
但如你所说  你说话算数
but like you said, your word is your bond.
现在你面前就是个兑现这句话的机会
This is a chance for you to keep it,
也许现在我们可以重新好好认识一下了
and maybe now we can actually start off on the right foot.
好吧  哈维
Okay, Harvey.
我加入
I'm in.
两年五个月零十二天
Two years, five months, 12 days.
我对你多久没要过女人了
I'm not interested in hearing how long it's been
不感兴趣
since you got laid.
不  这是你还得在这里
No, that's exactly how long it's gonna be
待着的时间
until you walk out of here.
你是想让我现在就揍你吗
You trying to get me to attack you right here?
因为你再说它就要实现了
Because that's what's gonna happen.
我只是想告诉你
I'm just trying to tell you
再过六周你就能被保释
that you're eligible for parole in six weeks.
胡扯
Bullshit.
你不相信我
You don't believe me?
好吧  你自己看
All right, take a look for yourself.
都写在上面了
It's all right there.
你识字的  对吧
You can read, right?
是的  我识字
Yeah, I can read,
但我们跟你不一样  不是冒牌律师
but we're not all fake lawyers like you,
所以你赶紧说这上面到底是什么
so why don't you tell me what it is I'm looking at?
你在等待审判期间在监狱服刑的时间
The time you served while awaiting trial
没有被算入刑期
was never factored into your sentence.
你的律师失职了
Your lawyer dropped the ball.
他为什么要那么做
And why the hell would he do that?
因为有一条神秘法令
Because of an arcane statute
十个律师九个都不知道  但我知道
that nine out of ten lawyers don't know about, but I do.
你以为我不知道这是你的保护人
You think I don't know this is your protector's idea
用来保护你的把戏吗
to get me off your back?
没用的
'Cause it's not gonna work.
不  弗兰克
No, Frank.
哈维想的办法是让我告诉这些人
Harvey's idea was for me to tell these guys
你进来的真正原因
that the real reason you're here
是因为你做了线人
is because you're an informant.
你敢把这事告诉别人  我就杀了你
You tell that to one living soul, I'll kill you.
我想你该决定的是
I guess you have to decide
你真要在这儿继续待两年
if you really want to spend the next two years
就为了找我麻烦
trying to mess with me
还是要选择好好度过你剩下的生命
or salvage what's left of your life.
如果你真要为了报复哈维就选择
If you're really gonna pick getting back at Harvey
放弃自由
over your own freedom,
那你真是我见过的最可悲的混蛋了
you really are the sorriest son of a bitch I've ever met.
这儿到底是怎么回事
What the goddamn hell is going on in here?
看起来不错  不是吗
It's looking good, isn't it?
伙计  你算是上了死亡名单了
Okay, buddy, you just signed your death warrant.
我之前给了你三十天  现在改成三十分钟
I gave you 30 days, now you've got 30 minutes.
我觉得你没戏  老大
I don't think that's happening, boss.
我们不但要留下
Not only are we staying,
而且还要用你心爱的大办公室
but we're making your beloved bullpen
做我们的操作中心
the center of our operations,
因为你大哥修改了我们的租约
because your big bro amended our lease.
胡扯
This is bullshit.
哈维为什么要这么做
Why the hell would Harvey do that?
简单来说就是  我帮了他一个忙
Let's just say I helped him out of a jam.
这事没完  因为不管哈维做了什么
This isn't over, because whatever Harvey did,
他对合同法的了解可没我多
he doesn't know contracts like I do.
但你对合同法的了解又不如我
And you don't know them like I know them,
因为这个新租约比你妈妈还难破
because this new lease is tighter than your mom's ass.
就冲你这句话  我要告你诽谤
That's it. I am suing you for slander,
因为我妈妈一点都不难破
because my mom's ass is miles from tight.
我信了  哥们儿  那你尽管试好了
I'll take your word for it, bro, and bring it on,
因为虽然你是哈佛毕业律师
because you might be a Harvard-educated lawyer,
但我们耶鲁毕业的律师也不好惹
but I'm a Yale-educated lawyer,
而你我的区别在于
and the difference between me and you
我知道交易才能赚大钱
is I know the real money's in trading.
现在请你离开我的大办公室
Now get the hell out of my bullpen.
-哈维  -威廉
- Harvey. - William.
我有东西给你
I got something for you.
我猜是等我签的合约吧
I assume it's an engagement letter for me to sign.
这是你将要提交的证管会表格
It's the SEC form you're gonna have to file
用于购买南森・巴恩斯公司5%的股权
for buying 5% of Nathan Burns's company.
-你知道了  -我不光知道
- So you know. - I don't just know.
我买下一个董事会席位
I bought a seat at the table,
我有南森和董事会站在我这边
and I got Nathan and the board on my side.
一派胡言
Bullshit.
你们没人有胆量反对我
None of you have the balls to go up against me.
我不是来反对你的  威廉
I'm not here to go up against you, William.
我来是给你点小钱  买回你的股份
I'm here to buy your shares back at a tidy little profit
你可以用这点钱
so you can use it to hire
随便雇谁来当你的律师
whoever you want to be your lawyer
因为我肯定不会受雇于你的
because it sure as hell isn't gonna be me.
我也可以确保他的公司
Yeah, maybe instead I'll make sure his company
落进我的口袋  然后永远不雇你
gets in my pocket, never hires you,
让你的律所连这一季度都撑不过
and your firm is out of business by the end of the quarter.
那是不可能的
Well, that's never gonna happen,
因为唯一赢下这一局的办法
because the only way to win this thing
是自己趟进浑水搞一身泥
is to get down in the mud,
如果我是你的律师
and if I was gonna be your lawyer,
当然我绝对不会是
which I'm never gonna be,
我会告诉你  在你面对诉讼威胁时
I'd tell you that's the last place you want to be
最不该做的就是这件事
when you're staring down the barrel of an indictment.
你知道你这是在把我
You know you're making an enemy of me
变成你余生中的敌人
for the rest of your life.
随你便  哥们  因为我有一件
Take a number, buddy, because one thing
绝对不会做的事
I'm never gonna do is get involved
就是跟你这样的卑鄙小人扯上关系
with a shady piece of shit like you.
你要去看电影吗
So you going to the movie?
没这个打算
I wasn't planning on it.
那里漆黑一片  拥挤不堪
It's pitch black. Packed in.
加洛可能会找事
Gallo might try something.
你不是说过你有办法
I thought you said you had some way
摆脱他的么
to get him off our backs.
我还不知道能不能奏效
Yeah, I don't know if it worked yet or not.
那不重要  因为电影之夜是神圣的
Well, it doesn't matter, because movie night is sacred.
什么意思
What do you mean?
这是这里所有人都期待的夜晚
I mean it's one night that every guy in here looks forward to,
没人希望出事
you know, doesn't want to mess up.
谁在那里找事  结果都会
You try something in there, you're gonna end up
变成我老室友  马克・辛吉斯那样
like my old roommate, Mark Higgins.
今天要播什么
Well, what's playing?
《红潮风暴》[1995年电影]
"Crimson Tide."
你不是开玩笑吧
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
我跟你说了
Well, you heard what I said about
电影之夜是神圣的  对吧
the sanctity of movie night, right?
另外  我绝不会拿丹泽尔・华盛顿开玩笑
Besides, me, I never joke about Denzel.
"金刚跟我比根本不算啥
"King Kong ain't got shit on me!
不是我们踩上了普利茅斯岩"
We didn't land on Plymouth Rock."
"是普利茅斯岩压着我们了"
"Plymouth Rock landed on us."
真是该死
Shit.
这是什么
What's this?
你的新工作
That's your new job.
从现在开始  你跟他一起在厨房当值
From now on you're doing kitchen duty with him.
如果被我抓到你跟典狱长有接触
And if I catch you doing the warden,
就等着单独监禁吧
you're going to solitary.
我没要求去厨房当值
I didn't ask for kitchen duty.
或许没有  但我知道是谁给你的
Maybe not, but I think I know who gave it to you.
我听说你去见了威廉・萨特
I heard you went to see William Sutter.
总得有人去告诉他要死自己死
Someone had to tell him to drop dead in person.
我以为我们已经说好要签下他了
I thought we agreed we were gonna take him on.
那是在我给我们接到
That was before I made us legal counsel
东海岸一家大型能源制造商的法律顾问业务之前
for the largest energy producer on the East Coast.
你签下了南森・巴恩斯
You signed Nathan Burns?
是的
I did.
我希望你知道自己在做什么  哈维
Well, I hope you know what you're doing, Harvey,
因为我们本可以同时有两个客户的
Because we could have had them both.
杰西卡  我受过教训了
Jessica, I learned my lesson.
跟狗一起混  容易沾一身虱子
When you lie down with dogs, you come up with fleas,
我跟你说  我们做了对的事
And I'm telling you, we did the right thing.
那就放点音乐吧  因为我们重回赛场了
Then put some music on, because we're back on the map.
敬重回赛场
To being back on the map.
敬签下新客户
To drawing a new one.
-要叫上路易吗  -拜托
- Should we get Louis? - Aw, come on.
给他喝一口  我们就得听他讲
He takes one sip of this, we'll have to hear that story
他破处的故事
about the first time he got laid.
要听的是那个故事已经算幸运了
We'd be lucky if that's the story we get to hear.
你俩在喝酒
Wow, you guys are drinking?
你们还没听到我的消息呢
You haven't even heard my news yet.
你找到移送加洛的办法了
You figured out a way to get Gallo transferred?
比那还好
Even better.
我找到了让迈克提前出狱的办法
I figured out a way to get Mike out early.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding me.
你觉得我大老远跑来是为了骗你吗
You think I came all the way down here to bullshit you?
我们都知道天下没有免费的午餐
Well, we all know there's no such thing as a free lunch,
肖恩  代价是什么
Sean, so what's the catch?
他得告发一个狱友
He has to inform on one of his fellow inmates.
你怎么会觉得他能接近这个人
What makes you think he can even get close to this guy?
我觉得那不是问题
Oh, I don't think that's gonna be a problem.
那人是他的室友
It's his roommate.
听我说  迈克绝对不会这么做的
Listen to me, Mike's never gonna go for this.
你不如告诉我们你到底在说什么
So why don't you tell me what the hell you're talking about?
凯文・米勒是另一件案子的证人
Kevin Miller's a smoking gun on another case.
我们试过让他告发他的家族  但他不肯
We tried to get him to turn on his family but he wouldn't.
迈克让他开口  或者找到办法
Mike gets him to turn or figures out
弄到我们需要的证据  就自由了
how to get what we need out of him anyway, he's free.
你们什么时候要迈克的答案
When do you need an answer by?
昨天
Yesterday.
而且答案必须是接受
And the answer needs to be yes.